lestyn Gage

Software Engineer

lestyngage@gmail.com https://www.iestyngage.com Cardiff, CF14 0SS

Core Skills

Full-Stack Development
Web & Mobile Development
Troubleshooting & Debugging
Agile Methodology
Code Review
User Experience
Documentation
Team Collaboration

Programming Languages

JavaScript | TypeScript | HTML CSS Java | Swift | PHP | Python SQL

Tools

Git | Gitlab | GitHub | NodeJS Yarn | NPM | WSL | VSCode IntelliJ | Gradle | Jira | Excel Postman

Languages

English | First language Welsh | Basic proficiency

Interests

Kayaking | Cooking | Reading Gym | Baking | Cycling



Career summary

Growth-focused Full Stack Software Engineer with a one-year achievement record in agile environments and experience combining all facets of software, web, and mobile development. Verifiable proficiency in developing innovative products and applications. Committed to excellence, readable, testable, and maintainable code.

Professional Experience

CoreFiling | Oxford, England | Hybrid

Junior Software Engineer | 02/2021 – Present

Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, Java, HTML, CSS,

Frameworks: React, Swagger, Liferay

- Full-stack developer, with a focused on the front end.
- Pioneering new front-end pages and components to maximise usability, simplify navigation, and create a seamless user journey for a new product.
- Leveraging swagger to develop new APIs endpoints while also conducting simple implementation changes.
- Performed code review for major and minor changes to identify issues
- Supporting QA and PM to identify and address pain points, bugs, and issues.
- Facilitating knowledge sharing and streamlining README.md and getting started documentation to streamline developer onboarding process
- Methodically documenting and managing defects, partnering with other team members in developing and implementing resolutions, and accelerating product improvement.
- Coordinating major changes and successfully upgrading react router from version
 5 to 6

TalkOut Technology | Birmingham, England | Remote

Junior iOS Developer | 11/2020 – 12/2020

Languages: Swift,

Frameworks: SwiftUI, UIKit

- Supported a multi-discipline team in developing and releasing an iOS application.
- Produced UI tests and refactored generated code to enhance readability.
- Prototyped, and presented interactive widgets, increasing usability and enhancing the user experience.
 - Reason for leaving: Team made redundant

Aberystwyth University | Aberystwyth, Wales

Computer Science Demonstrator | 10/2018 – 12/2018

• Mentored, guided, and supported first-year students in various programming topics, fixed code, and marked assignments, empowering students to enhance their programming skills.

Education & Qualifications

2017-2020

Aberystwyth University
First Class Honours

BSc Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence University Projects:

• Designed, prototyped and created a Conference iOS application

- Conducted a user experience evaluation of two websites
- **Personal Projects**
- Created my own personal website using React and deployed via Heroku
- Created an Evolutionary Algorithm to complete Card Problem with Java and displayed the results with JavaFX

Referees available upon request